[Music]
hello my name is das i am the analytics
go to market specialist for aws in asean
thank you for joining us here today i'm
very excited to be here and have a
conversation with dr yao on fwd
insurance ai customer 360 journey
dr yao is the head of data at fwd group
he holds a phd in ai and has over 20
years of big data analytics experience
having served in multinational companies
including pinghan uob ibm and cisco dr
yao many of us have heard about fwd
insurance making insurance simple for
your customers please tell us more about
fwd insurance
first of all thanks for inviting me to
join the aws summit try to share after
the experience and our point of view so
fwd is one of the first growth
insurance company in asia pacific
we start our journey 2013
now we expand to night market across
asia pacific
so our brand
vision is want to change the people feel
about insurance to make products simple
and we are more digital savior
what were some of the reasons that
made fwd insurance come up with this
brand vision of making insurance simple
i traditionally
customer persist
insurance is more complicated
long page of the policy terms is not
easy to understand so that's why
after we want to change the people feel
about insurance which means simplify and
easy to understand okay so as one of
the 9.6 million customers that fwd
insurance has i understand what you mean
by making insurance simple for your
customers
but i'm sure there must be a lot of work
that fwd insurance must be doing in the
background to make insurance simple for
customers like me so from a data
perspective what is involved in making
insurance simple for customers like me
as you know after this is a customer-led
company we put our customer on the heart
at the back end we did a lot of job
and one of the first initiative we are
doing today is
to build single custom build which to
consolidate data from different systems
to form a single viewer customer to
understand the customer demographics
customer preference right and the
customer needs they enable us to serve
you right to provide the product you
like and also to simplify the claim
journey
so it's interesting that you mentioned
that single view of customer is one of
your most important initiatives so why
is a single view of customers so
important for fwd
based on the recent research from a
company called xperia right
57 of a customer right if you have a
good single viewer customer right they
have a thing of your customer experience
they will recommend
the product to their friends their
families
26 of the customers they will leave very
positive comments in your social medias
but for those companies without think of
your customer if the company recommended
irrelevant products right don't listen
to them
84 of them will leave the company
so that's why the think of your customer
is very critical
so yeah these are like truly
strong numbers so i'm keen to know when
you went on this journey of building
your single view of customer
did you face any challenges while you
were embarking on this journey yeah same
as other organizations we are facing a
lot of challenges
like for example right so today the data
is across different departments right
which is get
and secondly that the data quality is
not really good for example one of the
markets look at the customer phone
numbers
right 20 percent phone number is
invalidated
and third things because today different
department different system right have
good or different technologies
it's very hard to integrate data
together without the data lake
technologies
okay
so thank you for being so candid about
the challenges that you faced so how did
fwd insurance overcome the challenges
that you just described before we
implement the think of your customers
right this is the framework we are
working on the first one right is from
the people technology cultures right and
the process
processes is very important right and
to make the process happen that the data
government is one of the critical
enablers right with the data governance
you can have the data dictionary to
understand your data access and you have
the data lineage understand the data
flows
and also you have the data quality
metrics to see right how about how good
your data quality is that help you to
see how we can do a
data enrichment
and how you can
protect our customer privacy typically
for the pr data
secondly us is the
people right first of all right to make
the senior management team as an owner
for the data program secondly we need to
build a team right mix of different
skill sets data science data engineering
data architect then they can collaborate
together and mine the data with insights
third is the culture right so we always
promote data-driven decision cultures
that's when we provide a lot of
trainings to the different user
different abuse whatever technical
training or tool trainings or insights
sharing
last night is the technologies right
that's why i want to leverage the modern
technology like the data lake right and
data analytics right to manage the data
whatever structure data are structured
together
so doctor you know some of the points
that you mentioned so
these are like three things really stood
out for me right as common patterns that
we see
across all successful analytics projects
across our customer so the first thing
that stood out for me was the
involvement of fwd senior management in
your analytics program
the second was the focus that fwd put in
training your people and building a
culture of data
and the third thing which stood out for
me was from a technology design
perspective you were designing not just
based on your requirements today but
also what your requirements might be in
future
so i'm keen to know based on what you
have described
in reality what does fwd's single view
of customer look like
this is our
customer da framework in a conceptual
right
so
by
getting customer proper consensus right
with the pdp compliance right and
working with our partners we are
building this the customer dna
framework step by step for example
demographics right for the demographic
we're more focused on the customer life
stage and life event because we are
insurance company so that life stage
library is really production triggers
for example you have a kids
if you marry if ever you have a disaster
a new house have loans all this will
trigger the needs right secondly we want
to capture our customer interests right
then because we want to provide more
personal communication to them that's
what i'm going to capture in terms of
travel in terms of finance then we can
provide the right service
right or tailor service for them
the third thing is we are captured today
for example is is the customer needs
right
either can get the input from the
customer we also can leverage the
machine learning models to see for
people like you what kind is you need
but sometimes people don't really know
what they want what they need so that's
how we can mine the data to come out a
recommendation for them
and we also focus on
we call voice of customers people want
to hear from them right whatever happy
not happy whatever and and not typically
what the mps score for that then give us
more insights how we can serve our
customer better
it does continuous journey right so in
the future we also plan to to capture
the iot data typically for the well
variable equipment
working with our strategy partners then
we can have more information about
customer health then we can provide more
dynamic price for them
that's awesome and one of the most
comprehensive descriptions of a customer
360 that i have seen so i'm curious to
understand what are some of the
technology components which have enabled
you to build your customer 360.
i think first of all we need to
have the data lake technology right
for example right we for the data
indications we need to leverage the aws
stream to consolidate data and and store
the data right then we also leverage
the the aws analytic service then we
mine data to come out different insights
we just mentioned right that use machine
learning to understand what was the
coverage guy what's next special for
that
and
the solutions that you described just
now so from a time frame perspective how
much time did it take fwd to build your
technology solution with a strong
support from aws i think i'm glad to
share all of you
we complete our facebook just in six
months
so six months is like super fast
and once the project went live what are
some of the business benefits that fwd
got from this project
i just show you one example right and
this is just launched
last year so this is the customer
trustee dashboard to show the customer
demographics policy information right
information and and also what's the
household information typically the
the recent customer engagement
information last not least is the ai
recommendation i just mentioned right to
assess the coverage gap based on people
like you then what's the next best
product we can recommend to them
so this dashboard to enable our
telesales channel right to sell
additional policy a new policy to a
customer to provide additional
protection to our customers
in the past we achieved quite pretty
conversion rates roughly eight percent
we solved this customer trustee
dashboard and the ai recommendation
and we launched this and from last
january to december i'd like to share
good news we have uplift
the com over conversion rate for eight
percent to 14 which is
75 incremental
and typically for those high
propensities we can achieve 22 which
means that the conversion will show you
right the high conversion rate which we
can provide more tailored product to our
customers
so these are truly staggering business
outcomes congratulations to you dr yao
and the fwd team on the success of this
project thanks tess again and thanks all
for all the support from your team very
welcome
i'm keen to understand from you dr yao
in terms of some of the reasons why fwd
choose aws for your analytics program
i think first of all it's easy to start
and also pay by use
secondly
flexibility it's easy to scale
up and scale down
the third is
easy to integrate with other aws
applications for example aws connect
this we can provide our call center to
service to our customer
last not least
is the cost right
because aws separate storage and
competitions then help us to lower cost
excellent so thank you dr yao for
sharing your insights i truly enjoyed
this conversation and look forward to
continue to engage with fwd group on
your analytics program thank you thanks
for your invitation again so it's my
great pleasure to come here to share ftp
experience thank you
okay so dr yao mentioned the training is
one of the factors that enable the
success of the single view of the
customer program
so you have joined aws summit to learn
and you can keep the learning going
after the summit with these resources
from aws training and certification
we offer many free and on-demand digital
courses as well as virtual
instructor-led training aws experts will
help you or your team to learn and build
and validate your data analytics skills
when you are ready prepare for the aws
certified data analytics speciality exam
which validates your skills and provides
industry recognized credential
thank you for your time today and hope
you enjoyed this session please do take
a few minutes to complete the session
survey thank you